# **THOMAS STYRON – SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Branson, MO | 432-386-2936 | thomasstyron@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

#### SUMMARY

Full-stack software engineer proficient in using Javascript for front-end and back-end programming, React HTML5, CSS, API implementing, Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, and frameworks like BootStrap. Experience in wilderness expedition planning and execution provides an advantage finding solutions in the face of adversity and seeing projects through to successful outcomes.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, jQuery

Backend: Node.js, Express, RESTful APIs, PostgreSQL

Tools: Mocha, Chai, Knex, Git, GitHub, Node Package Manager, Visual Studio Code, Dbeaver, ElephantSQL

Additional Skills: project management, Spanish

## SOFTWARE ENGINEERING PROJECTS

Restaurant Reservation Application | Thinkful | Reservations

08/2023

- Full stack reservation and table management system.
- Implemented react router and express to build a RESTful API in order to make HTTP requests for all the reservation data stored on the connected PostgreSQL database.
- Created CRUD functions and knex queries to handle data going to and coming from the database.
- Used Git to track changes and versions while keeping sensitive information from being pushed to repositories.
- Technology: React, Node.js, Express, Knex and PostgreSQL.

## Movie Database Application | Thinkful | WeLoveMovies

07/2023

- Assembled the back end of a movie website allowing any user to search for their favorite movies.
- Used CRUD methods for reviews, and view theaters and movies that are showing.
- Applied router and controller functions to retrieve a user's specific requests.
- Technology: Node.js, Express, and Knex. Version control with Git.

#### Front End Study Tool Application | Thinkful | Flashcards

06/2023

- Created an application that allows users to create, edit, and delete decks and study cards within them.
- Created a REST API and middleware functions to allow user(s) to create, read, update and delete.
- Applied router and controller functions to retrieve a user's specific requests.
- Technology: JavaScript, React, Express, Knex, HTML and CSS. Progress/Versions tracked with Git

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

O.A.R.S. et al.

*American West* 05/2004 -10/2023

## Wilderness Guide

- Led expeditions through wilderness areas of western United States.
- Obtained licenses and certifications for technical rescue, food service hazard management, and medical rescue designed for wilderness.

 Educated trip clients on importance of natural environment and their role in the continuing preservation of Earth's wild areas.

Copper Mountain Ski Resort

Frisco, CO 12/2021 - 08/2022

#### **Restaurant Manager**

- Managed day-to-day operations of a busy resort restaurant.
- Facilitated smooth operating conditions through pandemic conditions of 50% employee loss.
- Improved staff efficiency to ascertain record sales with minimal overhead on more than 5 occasions.
- Oversaw daily reorganization of available resources to accommodate the number of patrons unseen in prior seasons utilizing multi-restaurant (5) coordination to ensure best possible experience.

Far Flung Outdoor Center

*Terlingua, Texas* 10/2008 - 04/2020

## **Activity and Operations Manager**

- Utilized multiple software programs daly to make reservations, file and execute maintenance tickets, point of sale in retail and food and beverage, custom expedition price proposal and equipment inventory.
- Designed and customized expeditions to fit client needs while complying with the rules and regulations of various entities including the National Park Service, Texas Parks & Wildlife, and private landowners.
- Filtered applications and resumes for more than 200 prospective employees and improved employee retention from year to year by 40% when compared to previous managers.
- Troubleshooting logistics daily from transportation in a remote 3,000 sq. mile area to working with commercial grocers for efficient delivery times for perishable food items.
- Improved staff efficiency to ascertain record sales with minimal overhead on more than 5 occasions.

### **EDUCATION**

Thinkful

Online

#### **Certificate, Software Engineering**

04/2023 - 09/2023

- Learned industry best practices and software development standards with a focus on Javascript, HTML5,
  CSS3, React Native, Node.js, PostgreSQL, RESTful API's, algorithms, and data structures.
- Developed and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks, spending several hours per week collaborating with senior web developers in a mentor-student relationship.